mercurymarine.com 2014-05-29

# Privacy Policy | Mercury Marine

**Effective Date: January 5, 2011**

Brunswick Corporation and its divisions value its relationship with you and respect your concerns about privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to the online practices of Brunswick ([http://www.brunswick.com](http://www.brunswick.com/)) and the websites of its divisions and subsidiaries, a list of which is included at the end of this Policy, as posted.

This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Policy also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also provide information on how you may reach us to update your contact information, remove your name from our mailing lists, or get answers to questions you may have about our privacy practices at these websites.

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

You may choose to provide personal information, such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address online via our websites. We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information you may provide on our websites. The ways in which personal information may be submitted and/or used are as follows:

##### Careers

Our websites may include a link to Brunswick Careers in order that you may search for open positions at Brunswick and possibly submit your resume and other information, such as your name, contact information, and job history. We use the information you submit to evaluate your interest in employment and to contact you regarding possible employment.

##### Children’s Privacy

We recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of children. For this reason, we do not collect or maintain information from children we know are under thirteen (13) years of age, except as permitted by law.

##### Contact Us

If you choose to communicate with us through the Contacts or Contact Us link on our websites, we may ask you for information, such as your name, email address and telephone number so that we can respond to your questions and comments. We and/or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area may use the information to send you the communications you request and to communicate with you about our products and services. If you would like to update your contact information or preferences, have your information removed from our mailing lists, or no longer wish to receive marketing emails resulting from information collected via product registration cards or other sources, you may: email us at [privacy@brunswick.com](mailto:privacy@brunswick.com), call us at (847) 735-4318, or write us at Brunswick Corporation, Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, 1 North Field Court, Lake Forest, IL 60045.

##### E-Cards

From time to time, some of our sites may offer customers the ability to send e-cards. Email addresses and messages are requested, but are not collected. They are used strictly for e-card email delivery purposes.

##### Email Information

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. If you give us your email address, we may send you a welcoming email that may verify password and user name information. If you wish to unsubscribe from email contact, follow the directions in the email or use the contact information at the end of this policy to remove your name from the database.

##### Feedback, Surveys, or Contests

From time to time we may ask you to participate in online surveys, solicitations, or contests. Additional information requested may include contact information (such as email address) and demographic information (such as number of family members and income ranges). Participation in surveys, solicitations, or contests is completely voluntary. Therefore, you have a choice as to whether to disclose any information. We, or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area, will use the information provided to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor or improve the use of one or more sites or advertising, and to provide aggregated information for marketing analysis. This information will be used to analyze your present and future needs related to our products, to communicate with you about our products and services, and to send you further notices, promotions, solicitations, or brochures, and other marketing materials regarding our websites, our products, and the services of our businesses and the businesses of our affiliates, business partners, or authorized dealers/service providers, unless we have been notified that you do not wish to be contacted for marketing concerns. Solicitations may take the form of mailings via U.S. mail or other couriers, or email (if provided).

##### Information Request

If you request information about our products, such as ordering a brochure, a catalogue or a magazine, we may ask you to provide details such as your name, email address, telephone number, intended use of the relevant product, center of interests, etc. You may also choose to provide additional comments and requests. We and/or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area may use your personal information to respond to your request and to communicate with you in the future about our products and services.

##### Locate an Authorized Dealer or Service Provider

You may want to locate an authorized dealer or service provider near you by completing a "find your dealer" request form through our websites. We ask you for information, such as your first and last name, full postal address and telephone number. We use this information to locate an authorized dealer or service provider near you, to evaluate your needs, and to give you the best and most relevant service. We and/or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area may use the information to send you the communications you request and to communicate with you about our products and services.

##### Newsletters and Other Communications

From time to time, our sites may offer online or offline newsletters and other communications about our products, services and promotions. To sign up, we will ask you for information such as your name, postal address and email address. We and/or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area may use the information to send you the communications you request and to communicate with you about our products and services.

##### Online Sales

Our branded merchandise and/or gift cards may be offered for sale by an authorized merchandise partner through a website they own and control which is linked to one of our websites. Your purchase will be conducted on our authorized merchandise partner's website and you should, therefore, review the privacy policy and terms of use that apply to that third party’s website.

##### Online Sales by Brunswick Companies

The following Brunswick companies sell products directly from their websites: [tritonboats.com](http://www.tritonboats.com/) and [tritonboats.net](http://www.tritonboats.net/), [brunswickbilliards.com](http://brunswickbilliards.com/), [brunswick-billiards.com](http://brunswick-billiards.com/), [mercurymarine.com](http://mercurymarine.com/), [mercurypartsexpress.com](http://mercurypartsexpress.com/), and [boatingstore.com](http://boatingstore.com/). Your information is collected for shipping, billing, product notices, and customer service assistance.

##### Credit Refinancing Site

In some instances, we may make available through our sites, an indivisible linked site of a third party vendor for credit refinancing for some of our products. Your information goes directly to the third party vendor and is not received by our companies. You should review the privacy policy and terms of use that apply to the third party vendor’s website.

##### Other Features

We offer consumers and customers various features on our websites for their information and enjoyment, which we may change from time to time. We may ask you to submit certain personal information in order that we or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area may use the information to provide you with these features or to communicate with you in the future about our products and services.

##### Other Uses of Information

We may use the personal information you provide for internal purposes. These purposes include administration, data analytics and compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.

##### Owner’s Programs or Rewards Programs

Some of our sites may offer owner’s programs, reward programs, or coupons and request contact information and information on your product purchases so that we can enroll you in these programs and communicate with you.

##### Price Quote

From time to time, some of our sites may offer customers the ability to enter contact information and product or event preferences for a price quote for our products or event packages.

##### Product Registration

From time to time, our sites may offer online product registration. By registering your product online, you agree to that we, an authorized dealer/service provider, affiliate, or third party advertising agency (provided that such third party advertising agency is similarly restricted in their use of the information) may contact you in order to provide product notifications, as required by law, for customer service and/or warranty assistance, to maintain Brunswick’s databases and business processes, and/or to contact you for purposes otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy.

##### Referral Service

We may offer a referral service that allows you to inform your friends and other acquaintances about products and/or information contained on (or through) Brunswick’s websites. If you elect to use such a referral service, the following will apply: email address(es) will be collected for the purpose of sending a one-time email for which you will be noted as the sender of such email (and we will be a service provider facilitating such delivery).

##### Registration for Business Opportunities

Some of our websites may offer registration of personal information for business opportunities for our authorized dealers and distributors or opportunities and sponsorships associated with selling, buying, or using our products.

##### Reminders/Registration for Upcoming Events

From time to time, some of our sites may offer reminders of upcoming events or registrations for those events, and we collect your contact information to fulfill your request.

##### Electronic Delivery for Shareholders

If you are a Brunswick shareholder and would like to receive shareholder materials by email, we ask you to register for this service on the [Brunswick.com](http://brunswick.com/) website. Registering will also allow you to vote your shares online. To register, if you are a shareholder in the United States or Canada, you must provide your Social Security number or tax ID number, your email address and a 4-digit PIN. If you are a shareholder in a country other than the United States or Canada, you must provide your Brunswick shareholder account number, your email address and a 4-digit PIN. We use the information you provide to verify that you are a Brunswick shareholder, to register you for the electronic delivery service, and to provide you with the electronic delivery and voting services you requested. You may also update or cancel your registration on the site by providing the same information.

##### "Ship's Log" Smartphone Application

We, or the authorized dealer/service provider in your area, may use the information collected to monitor or improve the use of one or more sites or advertising and to provide aggregated information for marketing analysis. This information may also be used to analyze your present and future needs related to our products, to communicate with you about our products and services, and to send you further notices, promotions, solicitations, or brochures, and other marketing materials regarding our websites, our products, and the services of our businesses and the businesses of our affiliates, business partners, or authorized dealers/service providers, unless we have been notified that you do not wish to be contacted for marketing concerns. Solicitations may take the form of email, or mailings via U.S. mail or other couriers (if physical address is provided). Information provided for use with the Ship's Log website will be available to the general public via the internet, wherein the information may include boat name, images, location, title of user's log, notes or tags about user's log, and engine operating information.

#### INFORMATION WE COLLECT BY AUTOMATED MEANS

We collect certain information by automated means when you visit our websites, such as how many users visited our websites and the pages that were accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our websites to our visitors. We collect this information through various means such as "cookies" and "web beacons." In addition, we may collect IP addresses, as explained below.

##### Cookies

Like many companies, we use "cookies" on our websites. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. We use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website features.

##### IP Addresses

An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our websites, we may view the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. We use this information to determine the general physical location of the device and understand from what regions of the world our website visitors come. We may also use this information to enhance our websites.

##### Web Beacons

Certain pages on our websites contain "web beacons" (also know as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information, such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the web beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the web beacon appears, the time the page containing the web beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party.

#### INFORMATION WE SHARE

We do not sell or otherwise disclose information about our website visitors, except as described here. We may share the information you provide among our subsidiaries and affiliates, and with Brunswick business partners, such as our joint marketing partners, authorized dealers/service providers and distributors, for our products which are solely authorized to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity or (iv) if this is necessary to protect the vital interests of the person.

If you are a California resident, you may ask us to refrain from sharing your information with third parties and among our affiliates for their marketing purposes, if the affiliates are separate legal entities. Please tell us your preference by contacting us as indicated in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use information you have provided through our websites in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

#### LINKS TO OTHER SITES

Our websites may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from this site. Linked sites may have their own privacy policy which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not part of this site, we are not responsible for their content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

#### HOW WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information you provide on our websites.

#### INFORMATION WE TRANSFER

The websites to which this Privacy Policy applies are subject to United States law, unless otherwise provided herein. We may transfer the personal information we collect on this site to other countries where we do business, which may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described here, even though a given country may not have the same privacy and data protection laws as the country in which you reside.

##### Policy Jurisdiction

This policy is the general privacy policy for the United States and other jurisdictions not otherwise specifically covered by the jurisdiction-specific policies for the European Economic Area (“EEA”). The General Privacy Policy also applies to citizens of the EEA, except where the provisions of the General Privacy Policy and the EEA Policy cannot be construed consistently, the provisions of the respective EU or Canadian Policy will govern.

##### EEA Privacy Policy

The attached EEA Privacy Policy (in English) concerns only consumer and customer personal information transferred from the EEA to the United States. Brunswick’s Privacy Policy applies to consumers/customers of the EEA except where the provisions of this Privacy Policy and the EEA Privacy Policy cannot be construed consistently, in which case the provisions of the EEA Privacy Policy will govern. If you are a job applicant located in an EEA country and would like to receive more information on Brunswick’s Human Resources privacy practices, please refer to the “How to Contact Us” section at the end of this Privacy Policy. Please refer to http://www.export.gov/safeharbor to learn more about the European Directive on Data Protection.

##### Safe Harbor

Brunswick’s policy regarding the collection, storage, transfer, use and other processing of personal information of EEA citizens is to comply with the Safe Harbor principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity, and enforcement and oversight.

#### UPDATES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will post a prominent notice on this site to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.

#### ACCESS AND CORRECTION

We provide website visitors with reasonable access to personal information they provide through our sites and the ability to review and correct it, as applicable. To help protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password and user ID before granting access to your information.

#### HOW TO CONTACT US

If you would like to update your contact information or preferences, or have your information removed from our mailing lists, you may:

  * e-mail us at: [privacy@brunswick.com](mailto:privacy@brunswick.com)
  * call us at: **(847) 735-4318**
  * write us at: **Brunswick Corporation, Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, 1 North Field Court, Lake Forest, IL 60045**
